Sambuu Uugansuren

Personal Information

Date of Birth: 1994-05-13 Nationality: Mongolia

Address: 121-0815 Japan, Tokyo, Adachi, Shimane 4-38-9, Ardor 304

Phone number: 080-4009-4717 **Email address:** mongolism@gmail.com

Profile

System engineer with 6 years of working experience including 4 years in infrastructure development for cloud computing platforms. Extensive experience in transitioning customers from on-premise solutions to cloud-based deployments, utilizing cloud infrastructure to solve problems related to on-site computing and optimizing solutions. Provider of smooth, well-planned transition architecture.

Work Experience

2018-06 — present Tokyo, Japan

System engineer

Data Artist Inc

- Contribute to each project delivery phase (analysis, development, test, ops) in multiple roles as Bridge engineer, Lead engineer and Dev-Ops.
- Deliver new features in both Agile and SDLC life-cycles.
- Implement various microservices for AI Projects with serverless infrastructure, AWS and GCP as a platform. Achieved cost reduction with "pay-as-you-go", great performance with auto-scaling.
- Automate build, testing, deployment, reporting with CICD on various projects.
- Manage outsourcing projects as "Bridge engineer" overseeing development teams between 2 countries.
- Led a team up-to 6 developers as "Lead engineer".
- Reduced cost by 55.37% on monthly fee of AWS billing.
- Performance improvement optimization of 121.96% on image generating projects.
- Serverless web application development including Frontend with Vuejs and Typescript, Amplify on the Backend. Machine learning models deployed on Fargate with autoscaling settings.
- Serving microservices on Lambda functions as a Funcion-as-a-Service structure, including Python and Nodejs runtime environment.

2015-06 - 2018-06Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia

Full stack developer

Sodon Solution LLC

- Conceived and built optimized landing pages in HTML and CSS, including third-party software integration and cross-browser compatibility, to support marketing.
- Optimized platform of multiple websites hosting CMS as a backend.
- Managed development milestones from initial steps through final delivery.
- Consulted with engineering team members to determine system loads and develop improvement plans.
- Developed multiple websites serving backend on Spring Framework with Java.
- Frontend development with JSP / JSTL library on every project.

Education

2010-09 - 2014-06Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia Computer Science / Bachelor

Mongolian University of Science and Technology

Skills

DEVELOPMENT SKILLS

- DEVELOPMENT SKILLS			
AWS	GCP	JavaScript	Python
•	•	· •	•
Java	SQL	NoSQL	Shell
•	•	•	•
Daaliaa	Odreal a OT	O. t	W
Docker	CircleCI	Git	Vuejs
-			•

Reactis

- LANGUAGES

English **ADVANCED**

Japanese BUSINESS

Mongolian NATIVE

Other